Guide to the Michael Fraenkel Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Michael Fraenkel papers
1911-2002
GEN MSS 891
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
6.47
(16 boxes)
The collection consists of writings, correspondence, personal papers, and printed material, documenting the work of avant-garde writer and publisher Michael Fraenkel and his publishing company Carrefour Press, as well as the work of his wife Daphne Fraenkel who continued as director of the publishing company after Fraenkel's death and their literary executor Michael Peter Harris.
Fraenkel, Michael, 1896-1957
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Moirandet Company AG on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Michael Fraenkel (1896-1957)
Michael Fraenkel was born in Kopul, Lithuania, in 1896 and immigrated to New York City with his parents in 1903. He graduated from the City College of New York, and moved to Paris in 1926 to write. He formed a publishing company in Paris with Walter Lowenfels called Carrefour Press. While in Paris, he also befriended Henry Miller and is thought to have been an early yet important influence on Miller. Fraenkel's published works include: Anonymous: The Need for Anonymity (with Walter Lowenfels, 1930); Bastard Death: The Autobiography of an Idea (1936); Death in a Room: Poems 1927-1930 (1936); Hamlet (with Henry Miller, 1941-1943; later republished as The Michael Fraenkel - Henry Miller Correspondence Called Hamlet, 1962); and Land of the Quetzal (1946).
Fraenkel married Daphne Moschos Gillam in 1953. After Fraenkel's death in 1957, Daphne Fraenkel continued as director of Carrefour until her death in 1991. Before her death, she appointed Michael Peter Harris as literary executor and custodian of the Carrefour Publishing Company.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of writings, correspondence, personal papers, and printed material, documenting the work of avant-garde writer and publisher Michael Fraenkel and his publishing company Carrefour Press, as well as the work of his wife Daphne Fraenkel who continued as director of the publishing company after Fraenkel's death and their literary executor Michael Peter Harris.
Writings include typescript drafts of works by Fraenkel, including essays, reviews, and an unpublished work, Mexican Journal, parts of which were published as Land of the Quetzal (1946). Correspondence consists primarily of incoming letters to Michael and Daphne Fraenkel, in addition to some outgoing letters and letters from Fraenkel to his wife. Personal papers include passports, marriage and death certificates, notes, printed versions and clippings of reviews of Fraenkel's work. Carrefour Press papers primarily consist of correspondence received by Michael Peter Harris from 1991 to 2000, in addition to some earlier correspondence, business files, and manuscript submissions by various authors.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Writings, 1911-1944. II. Correspondence, 1932-1993. III. Personal Papers, 1948-1959. IV. Daphne Fraenkel Papers, 1918-1993. V. Carrefour Press Papers, circa 1939-2002.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century; Authors, English -- 20th Century; English literature -- 20th Century; Publishers and publishing -- 20th Century; Authors; Publishers; Fraenkel, Daphne; Fraenkel, Michael, 1896-1957; Harris, Michael Peter; Carrefour Press
- Writings, 1911-1944; Series I; 1.67; (4 boxes)
  - Mexican Journal, orginal working copy, typescript, corrected, 1941-1944 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - Mexican Journal (The War Years), typescript M/S no.2, 1940-1944 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Mexican Journal (The War Years), typescript M/S no. 3, 1940-1943 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
  - Mexican Journal (The Years Between 1940-1944), original copy, typescript (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mexican Journal, various drafts, undated (Box 2, Folder 10-20)
  - Essays
    - "Anonymous," typescript, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - "Paul Bartlett," typescript, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - "A Skeleton Draft of the Death," typescript, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - "Beyond the Bread Principle," typescript, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - "Brandes on Nietzsche," typescript, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - "On Nietzsche," typescript, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - "Freud and the Modern Writer," typescript, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - "On Freud," typescript, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - "Jerusalem- Spirit of Peace," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - "Israel & Jewish Youth in the Diaspora," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "Sabbath in Israel," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - "The Androgynous Act," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - "The Argentine Mind," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - "The Breakdown of Literary Action," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - "The Day Face and the Night Face," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - "The Genesis of Tropic of Cancer," (and related papers) typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - "The Otherness of D.H. Lawrence," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - "Notes on Reading the Sin of Saurat," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - "The State of Modern Poetry," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - "The Stricken Body," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - "The Word, the Writer, and Action," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - "Werther's Younger Brother," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - "Total Man and Evil," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - "What Israel Means to Me," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - "The World of Kapula," autograph manuscript, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - "The Failure in Action," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - "Moral Secession and Individual Action," typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Untitled essays, undated (Box 3, Folder 48-50)
    - Untitled essays, undated (Box 4, Folder 51-61)
  - Reviews
    - "Serge's Last Novel," typescript, undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - "The Jewish Apostate," typescript, undated (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - "The Ultimate Image," typescript, undated (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - "The Philosophy of Dialogue," typescript, undated (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - "God as Reality and Idea," typescript, undated (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - "The Akedah," typescript, undated (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - "The Story Without the Fire," typescript, undated (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - "By Works or Grace," typescript, undated (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - "The Dynamics of Faith," typescript, undated (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Poems, undated (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Death in a Room / La Mort en Chámbre, autograph manuscript and typescript, 1927-1930 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Early notes, autograph manuscript, 1911-1933 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Drafts and notes, autograph manuscript and typescript, undated (Box 4, Folder 74)
- Correspondence, 1932-1993; Series II; 1.88; (5 boxes)
  - Michael Fraenkel to Daphne Fraenkel, 1940-1945 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - Michael Fraenkel to Daphne Fraenkel, undated (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Michael Fraenkel to Daphne Fraenkel, telegrams, 1937-1955 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Michael Fraenkel to Daphne Fraenkel, envelopes, 1941-1955 (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - Michael Fraenkel, outgoing, 1939-1956 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - Michael Fraenkel and Daphne Fraenkel, incoming
    - ADAM International Review, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 80)
    - Adelson, Dorothy, undated (Box 6, Folder 81)
    - Albert, Douglas, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 82)
    - Arvonio, John, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 83)
    - Ashwood, Avery, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 84)
    - Baxte, Michael (poem transcribed by Daphne Fraenkel), undated (Box 6, Folder 85)
    - Barnes, Chas. E., 1951 (Box 6, Folder 86)
    - Benoít, Hubert, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 87)
    - Barbudo, Antonio Sánchez (essay, "Another Spain", and photograph), undated (Box 6, Folder 88)
    - Behrendt, Alfred, 1936-1941 (Box 6, Folder 89)
    - Braybrooke, Neville, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 90)
    - Briscoe, Orah, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 91)
    - The Brooklyn Citizen, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 92)
    - Buchet, Edmond, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 93)
    - Cabanas, Alfredo, undated (Box 6, Folder 94)
    - Calverton, V. F., 1939 (Box 6, Folder 95)
    - Cass, Bob, undated (Box 6, Folder 96)
    - Mrs. Charchat, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 96a)
    - Chamberlain, Miriam, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 97)
    - The Christian Century, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 98)
    - Cleveland Plain Dealer, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 99)
    - Coczeas(?), John, undated (Box 6, Folder 100)
    - Cohen, Benjamin, undated (Box 6, Folder 101)
    - Cohen, Henry, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 102)
    - Cohen, Marvin, undated (Box 6, Folder 103)
    - Cohen, Murray, undated (Box 6, Folder 104)
    - Cook, Peter B., 1957 (Box 6, Folder 105)
    - Coppage, Jessie, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 106)
    - Corbin, Dorcy, undated (Box 6, Folder 107)
    - Corner, Anne (Biederman), 1943-1955 (Box 6, Folder 108)
    - Coude, Victoria Weiner, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 109)
    - Cova, E., 1935 (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - Culler, Geoff, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - Culler, Effie Ewington(?), 1936 (Box 6, Folder 112)
    - DEATH, a literary quarterly, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 113)
    - diogenes, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 114)
    - Dohee, Bovary(?), 1936 (Box 6, Folder 115)
    - Duxbury, Peter (includes poem and illustration), 1940 (Box 6, Folder 116)
    - Erst, Stelio, 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 117)
    - The Examiner, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - Faÿ, Bernard, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - Finch, Roy, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - Finley, William, 1945-1972 (Box 6, Folder 121)
    - Flottermesch, Robert, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 122)
    - Franklin, Vivian, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 123)
    - Friedman, E. Fisher ("I Wear My Overcoat Buttoned", typescript), undated (Box 6, Folder 124)
    - Garcia, Rafael, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 125)
    - Garrigue, Jean (includes contract and poems), undated (Box 6, Folder 126)
    - Gaytán, Pelayo and Carmen, 1946-1948 (Box 6, Folder 127)
    - Gibian, Jefferey, 1953-1997 (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - Gray, Dorie, undated (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - Greer, Scott, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 130)
    - Gubbins, Stamer, 1954-1961 (Box 6, Folder 131)
    - Hall, Horace C., 1941 (Box 7, Folder 132)
    - Herberg, Will, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 133)
    - Hill, E. F. F., 1946 (Box 7, Folder 134)
    - Hought, Claude, 1942-1943 (Box 7, Folder 135)
    - Hurlyhi, James, undated (Box 7, Folder 136)
    - The Humanist, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 137)
    - Isaak, Mary Booth, 1941-1944 (Box 7, Folder 138)
    - Israel: Life and Letters, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 139)
    - Jaffe, Jean, 1944-1957 (Box 7, Folder 140)
    - Jakolev, ______, undated (Box 7, Folder 141)
    - The Jewish Quarterly, 1954-1960 (Box 7, Folder 142)
    - Karman, Louise, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 143)
    - Kern, Dorothy, undated (Box 7, Folder 144)
    - King, Abraham, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 145)
    - King, Anna, 1946-1966 (Box 7, Folder 146)
    - La Tour, Onya, 1950-1952 (Box 7, Folder 147)
    - Landou, Howard, undated (Box 7, Folder 148)
    - Lee, Muna, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 149)
    - Le Claire, Lesley, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 150)
    - Leinbach, Chapin R., undated (Box 7, Folder 151)
    - Leontief, Wassily, undated (Box 7, Folder 152)
    - La Llave del Saber, 1942-1945 (Box 7, Folder 153)
    - Lundkvist, Arthur, 1936-1940 (Box 7, Folder 154)
    - Lurie, Harold and Gertrude, 1953-1961 (Box 7, Folder 155)
    - Mairet, Philip, 1942-1955 (Box 7, Folder 156)
    - Maisonville, Jeanne, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 157)
    - Mangham, Herbert, 1943-1947 (Box 7, Folder 158)
    - Margules, Blanche, 1938-1953 (Box 7, Folder 159)
    - Maze(?), Philip, undated (Box 7, Folder 160)
    - McClean, Walter, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 161)
    - Miller, Henry (autograph note on letter from The Colt Press), 1942 (Box 7, Folder 162)
    - Milson, Sylvia, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - Mock, Hugo, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - Modern Review, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 165)
    - Monson, D., 1956 (Box 7, Folder 166)
    - Montgomery, Neil
      - Incoming, 1941-1957 (Box 7, Folder 167)
      - Outgoing, 1941-1951 (Box 7, Folder 168)
      - "Coal Black Mammy," typescript, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 169)
      - "Views and Reviews. Correspondence on Hamlet," typescript, undated (Box 7, Folder 170)
      - "Extract from Coal Black Mammy," typescript, undated (Box 7, Folder 171)
      - Xerox copy of "Coal Black Mammy", undated (Box 7, Folder 172)
    - Moxley, Bill, 1941-1942 (Box 7, Folder 173)
    - Muller, Herbert J., 1941 (Box 7, Folder 174)
    - Nelson, Ruth and Harry, 1955-1972 (Box 8, Folder 175)
    - Neuschotz, Gertrude Loey, 1945-1955 (Box 8, Folder 176)
    - New Republic, 1952-1954 (Box 8, Folder 177)
    - Pearce, Charles A., 1939-1948 (Box 8, Folder 178)
    - Perez, Giro Zarate, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 179)
    - Peter, Gustavo, undated (Box 8, Folder 180)
    - Pfefer, Max, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 181)
    - Pollinger, Laurence, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 182)
    - Powell, James, undated (Box 8, Folder 183)
    - Pringeuf, T., undated (Box 8, Folder 184)
    - Quilter, E., 1943-1950 (Box 8, Folder 185)
    - Rainer, Dachine, undated (Box 8, Folder 186)
    - Ramage, Emily, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 187)
    - Redifer, Perry, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 188)
    - Reed & Harris Publishers, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 189)
    - Regler, Gustav, 1945-1947 (Box 8, Folder 190)
    - Richard, Bette, undated (Box 8, Folder 191)
    - Schlumilch, Jan, 1949-1951 (Box 8, Folder 192)
    - Sewanee Review, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 193)
    - Southwest Review, 1947-1948 (Box 8, Folder 194)
    - Schwartz, J., undated (Box 8, Folder 195)
    - Simpson, Charlotte, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 196)
    - Sogga, Carolyn, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 197)
    - Sturge-Moore, Laura, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 198)
    - Symons, Mary, 1951-1959 (Box 8, Folder 199)
    - Tieman Family (includes photograph), 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 200)
    - Thomson, John, 1957-1993 (Box 8, Folder 201)
    - Tomasic, Irene, undated (Box 8, Folder 202)
    - Town and Country, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 203)
    - Uhle, Henry and Shirley, 1935-1993 (Box 8, Folder 204)
    - Valencia, Manuel, undated (Box 8, Folder 205)
    - Vistas, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 206)
    - Wahl, Jean, undated (Box 8, Folder 207)
    - Walker, Dorothea, 1955-1967 (Box 8, Folder 208)
    - Weatherby, Meredith, 1940-1955 (Box 8, Folder 209)
    - White, John, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 210)
    - Whitford, William G., 1951 (Box 8, Folder 211)
    - Williams, W. C., 1936 (Box 8, Folder 212)
    - Wimberly, Lowry C., 1946 (Box 8, Folder 213)
    - Wing, Edna, 1932-1945 (Box 8, Folder 214)
    - Wolfe, Harriett, undated (Box 8, Folder 215)
    - Young, Lafayette, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 216)
    - Zueler, Wolfgang, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 217)
    - Unidentified, 1941-1955 (Box 8, Folder 218-219)
  - Daphne Fraenkel, incoming
    - Alderton, Eric, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 220)
    - Artajo, Jose M., undated (Box 8, Folder 221)
    - Barou, Alec, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 222)
    - Birge, Vincent, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 223)
    - Boothby, Simon, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 224)
    - Centing, Richard, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 225)
    - Cochrane, Christopher, undated (Box 8, Folder 226)
    - Facer, Margaret (includes manuscript and typescript poems), 1952-1960 (Box 8, Folder 227)
    - Gruner, Marcia, undated (Box 8, Folder 228)
    - Hargraves, Michael, 1977-1993 (Box 9, Folder 229)
    - Herschberger, Ruth, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 230)
    - Higgins, C., 1969 (Box 9, Folder 231)
    - Hyman, Olga, 1963-1966 (Box 9, Folder 232)
    - Jackson, Mano, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 233)
    - Jones, Eva (includes typescript poems), 1960-1962 (Box 9, Folder 234)
    - Jovic, Vida, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 235)
    - Kaplan, Edward, 1968-1994 (Box 9, Folder 236)
    - King, Heath, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 237)
    - Knox, Estelle and Booth, 1975-1994 (Box 9, Folder 238)
    - Lakhani, B. P., 1973 (Box 9, Folder 239)
    - The Landsdowne Press (Lambeth) Limited, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 240)
    - Leachman, James, 1967-1969 (Box 9, Folder 241)
    - Liles, Bernard, 1957-1971 (Box 9, Folder 242)
    - Lundstrom, Lucy, 1973-1978 (Box 9, Folder 243)
    - McCord, Howard, 1964-1995 (Box 9, Folder 244)
    - Muhlstock, Saul, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 245)
    - Musgrave, Sylvia, undated (Box 9, Folder 246)
    - Neal, Michael, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 247)
    - Norwood, Audrey, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 248)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 9, Folder 249)
    - Parsons, Benny, undated (Box 9, Folder 250)
    - Paulton, Richard, 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 251)
    - The Phoenix, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 252)
    - Richey, Laura and Mary Jane, 1970-1974 (Box 9, Folder 253)
    - Rigge, J. S., 1971 (Box 9, Folder 254)
    - Séjourné, Larette, undated (Box 9, Folder 255)
    - Seviour, Michael, 1963-1965 (Box 9, Folder 256)
    - Solomon, Ricardo, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 257)
    - Stanewick, Richard J., 1967-1971 (Box 9, Folder 258)
    - Staunton, Michael A., undated (Box 9, Folder 259)
    - Symondo, Jean, undated (Box 9, Folder 260)
    - Tamrin, Igor, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 261)
    - Tellos, George J.-J., 1969 (Box 9, Folder 262)
    - Travers, Michael, 1957-1970 (Box 9, Folder 263)
    - Van Goudareu(?), H. W., 1990 (Box 9, Folder 264)
    - Walker - de Berry Publishers, 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 265)
    - Warwick, Christopher, undated (Box 9, Folder 266)
    - Wenning, Henry W., 1967 (Box 9, Folder 267)
    - Wroom, Susan, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 268)
- Personal Papers, 1948-1959; Series III; 0.42; (1 box)
  - Autobiographical notes, 1948-1956 (Box 10, Folder 269)
  - Last will and testament, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 270)
  - "Committee for the Friends of Michael Fraenkel", undated (Box 10, Folder 271)
  - Photographs of Michael Fraenkel, undated (Box 10, Folder 272)
  - Passport and other official documents, undated (Box 10, Folder 273)
  - Biographical notes and bibliography, undated (Box 10, Folder 274)
  - Printed Versions of Fraenkel's Writing, undated (Box 10, Folder 275)
  - Reviews and other comments on Fraenkel's writings, undated (Box 10, Folder 276-280)
- Daphne Fraenkel Papers, 1918-1993; Series IV; 0.42; (1 box)
  - Notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 281-283)
  - Application to teach at the University of Illinois, 1948-1949 (Box 11, Folder 284)
  - Official papers, 1937-1992 (Box 11, Folder 285)
  - Obituary, 1989-1991 (Box 11, Folder 286)
  - Notes, aphorisms, undated (Box 11, Folder 287)
  - Letters to friends, 1937-1973 (Box 11, Folder 288)
  - Letter to the Gutkins, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 289)
  - Early correspondence, 1918-1993 (Box 11, Folder 290)
  - Correspondence with Michael Harris, 1958-1990 (Box 11, Folder 291)
  - Letters to Daphne Fraenkel, 1949-1977 (Box 11, Folder 292)
- Carrefour Press Papers, circa 1939-2002; Series V; 2.09; (5 boxes)
  - Business correspondence, circa 1939-1994 (Box 12, Folder 293-295)
  - Michael Harris Files (includes notes, correspondence, and literary executor contract), 1982-1998 (Box 12, Folder 296-299)
  - Michael Harris Files (includes notes, correspondence, and literary executor contract), 1989-1998 (Box 13, Folder 300-305)
  - Michael Harris Files (includes notes, correspondence, and literary executor contract), 1993-2000 (Box 14, Folder 306-312)
  - General Correspondence and related material
    - Ambre, Ruth, 1994-1998 (Box 15, Folder 313)
    - Armbruster, Sam, undated (Box 15, Folder 314)
    - Ashley, Bill, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 315)
    - Black Sparrow Press, 1991-1992 (Box 15, Folder 316)
    - Chloe's Books, undated (Box 15, Folder 317)
    - Circle, undated (Box 15, Folder 318)
    - Clarke, Graham, undated (Box 15, Folder 319)
    - Crews, Judson, 1993-1999 (Box 15, Folder 320)
    - Davey, William, 1998-1999 (Box 15, Folder 321)
    - Davidson, C. S., 1992 (Box 15, Folder 322)
    - Flach, Victor, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 323)
    - Ford, Hugh, 1991-1993 (Box 15, Folder 324)
    - Gay, Karl, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 325)
    - Greenman, Richard, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 326)
    - Grehn, Magnus, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 327)
    - Grob, Martina, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 328)
    - Hanson, Bill, 1994-1995 (Box 15, Folder 329)
    - Jackson, Roger, 1994-1998 (Box 15, Folder 330)
    - Joyce, William, 1995-2002 (Box 15, Folder 331)
    - Kostelanetz, Richard, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 332)
    - Lowenfels-Perpelitt, Manna, 1994-1998 (Box 15, Folder 333)
    - Ludwig, Karen, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 334)
    - Polyanthos Park Avenue Books, 1991-1992 (Box 15, Folder 335)
    - Savage, Derek, 1993-1997 (Box 15, Folder 336)
    - Selth, Jefferson, 1995-1998 (Box 15, Folder 337)
    - Sky Blue Press, 1995-1996 (Box 15, Folder 338)
    - Standish Books, 1993-1996 (Box 15, Folder 339)
    - Stanewick, Richard, 1993-1996 (Box 15, Folder 340)
    - Stone, Will, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 341)
    - Stroker Press, 1992-1996 (Box 16, Folder 342)
    - Stuhlmann, Gunther, 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 343)
    - Thompson, Tom, 1994-1996 (Box 16, Folder 344)
    - Vivier, Guillaume, 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 345)
    - Wilday, Michelle, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 346)
    - Miscellaneous notes, poems, and letters, undated (Box 16, Folder 347)
  - Carrefour stationery, undated (Box 16, Folder 348)
  - Copyright documents, 1939-1992 (Box 16, Folder 349)
  - Contracts, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 350)
  - Book lists, shipping lists, printed announcements, undated (Box 16, Folder 351)
  - Gordon, Harris, "Survivor's Way," printed, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 352)
  - Bartlett, Elizabeth, "It Takes Practice Not to Die," printed, undated (Box 16, Folder 353)
  - Dego, Giuliano, "The Italian Professor," copy of transcript, undated (Box 16, Folder 354)
  - Preston, Edward, "The Earth People," typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 355)
  - Kaplan, Edward K., "The Metaphysics of Creative Imagination of Gaston Bachelard," typescript, undated (Box 16, Folder 356)